成为美洲杯冠军是什么感觉？
What does it feel like to be champion of the Copa América?
¿Qué se siente ser campeón de la Copa América?
这是一个非常伟大的骄傲。
It is a very great pride.
Es un orgullo muy grande.
巨大的幸福是值得的。
an immense happiness that is worth it.
una felicidad inmensa que se vale.
为人民、为我们的家人带来欢乐，他们是受苦受难的人，是......
A joy to the people, to our family, who are the ones who suffer, the ones who are...
Una alegría a la gente, a nuestra familia, que son las que sufren, las que están...
这一年与我们在一起，事实是所取得的成就是......
with us throughout the year and the truth is that what was achieved was...
con nosotros durante todo el año y la verdad que lo que se consiguió fue...
这是美丽且具有历史意义的事情。
It was something beautiful and historic.
Fue algo hermoso y histórico.
您首先想到的是什么？
What was the first thing that came to your mind?
¿Qué fue lo primero que se te vino a la cabeza?
当他们完成比赛时，当他们标志着结束时。
when they finish the game, when they mark the end.
cuando terminan el partido, cuando marcan el final.
没什么，显然你脑子里有很多图像，一切......
Nothing, obviously you have a lot of images in your head, everything...
Nada, obviamente que se te vienen muchas imágenes en la cabeza, todo lo que...
为了到达那一刻，你这一年所做的工作，家人，朋友，显然
what you work during the year to get to that moment, family, friends, obviously
lo que trabajás durante el año para llegar a ese momento, la familia, los amigos, obviamente
组里，因为不管你喜不喜欢，45天都被关起来。
the group, because whether you like it or not, 45 days locked up.
el grupo, porque quieras o no, 45 días encerrados.
与同事一起生成 24-7...
24-7 there with colleagues is generated...
Las 24-7 ahí con los compañeros se genera...
一个非常强大和良好的联盟，能够实现它并像这样加冕，事实是它非常好。
a very strong and good union, to achieve it and crown it like this, the truth is that it is very nice.
una unión muy fuerte y bueno, conseguirlo y coronarlo así, la verdad que es muy lindo.
你已经是马拉卡纳的冠军了。
You had already been champion at the Maracaná.
Ya habías sido campeón en el Maracaná.
这届美洲杯对你个人来说有何不同？
What was the difference for you personally in this Copa América?
¿Cuál fue la diferencia para vos en lo personal en esta Copa América?
嗯，我认为每个杯子都有自己的东西。
Well, I think each glass has its own thing.
Bueno, creo que cada copa tiene lo suyo.
显然马拉卡纳队是......
Obviously the Maracaná one was...
Obviamente que la del Maracaná fue...
这很特别，因为它是在...之后喝的。
It was very special because it was a drink after...
Fue muy especial porque fue una copa después de...
这么多年为国家队对阵巴西队。
of so many years for the country against Brazil.
de tantos años para el país contra Brasil.
但事实上，这也很特别，因为一切......
But well, the truth is that this was also very special because of everything that...
Pero bueno, la verdad que esta fue muy especial también por todo lo que...
人们所谈论的是，能够两次成为美国冠军，是一个不小的壮举。
What has been talked about, being able to be two-time champion of America, is no small feat.
Lo que se venía hablando, poder ser bicampeón de América, no es poca cosa.
好吧。
And well.
Y bueno.
在美国，与其他球队一样，事实是……
in the United States, with other teams, the truth is that...
en Estados Unidos, con otras selecciones, la verdad que...
这非常激动人心，也非常特别。
which was very emotional and very special too.
que fue muy emotiva y muy especial también.
已经没有必要了。
It was already unnecessary.
ya era insuplementario.
您个人是如何经历这种情况的？斯卡罗尼对您提出了哪些要求？
How did you experience that situation personally and what did Scaroni ask of you?
¿Cómo viviste esa situación desde lo personal y qué fue lo que te pidió Scaroni?
嗯，我认为我们正在进入比赛的一个时刻，在加时赛中，
Well, I think we're entering a moment in the game where, in extra time,
Bueno, creo que entramos en un momento del partido donde por ahí en la prórroga ya
有很多球员已经积累了疲劳，所以他们开始创造更多的空间。
There are many players who are accumulating fatigue, so they begin to create more space out there.
Hay muchos jugadores que vienen acumulando fatiga, entonces se empiezan a crear más espacio por ahí.
让他热身是我们和那些热身的人谈论的事情。
Warming him up was what we talked about there a little with the guys who did.
Haciéndole entrada en calor era lo que hablábamos ahí un poco con los chicos que si
如果我们结合几次传球，我们可能会伤害他们，因为正在创造空间。
that if we combined several passes we could hurt them because spaces were being created.
que si juntábamos varios pases podíamos lastimarlos porque se estaban creando espacios.
好吧，利奥有点像他说的那样，就是这样，我们掌握了球，我们试图
and well, Leo was a bit like what he said, that's it, that we have the ball, that we try to
y bueno, Leo fue un poco lo que dijo, es eso, que tengamos la pelota, que tratemos de
游戏空间将会开放。
of playing that spaces are going to open up.
de jugar que se van a abrir los espacios.
他们已经变得混乱了，但他们也来了。
They were already getting messy, but they were also coming.
Ellos ya se estaban desordenando, pero también se venían.
幸运的是，我们发现奥迪能够转换这种玩法。
And well, luckily we found that play that the Audi was able to convert.
Y bueno, por suerte encontramos esa jugada que el Audi pudo convertir.
我认为从那时起，很明显这种情况可能会再次发生。
And I think that from there it was clear that it could happen again.
Y creo que a partir de ahí ya se veía que otra vez se podía dar.
你有多少次看到进球？
How many times did you see the goal?
¿Cuántas veces viste el gol?
你的朋友给你发了多少个 TikTok？
How many TikToks did your friends send you?
¿Cuántos TikTok te mandaron tus amigos?
您已经见过多少个平台？
How many platforms have you already seen?
¿En cuántas plataformas viste ya?
目标有多少次？
the goal and how many times?
el gol y cuantas veces?
事实上，赛后我见过他好几次。
The truth is that I saw him several times after the game.
La verdad que lo vi varias veces después del partido.
他们向你发送了视频、图像，但随后
that they were sending you the video, the images, but then
que te iban mandando el video, las imágenes, pero después ya
一旦它过去了，我就不再多看它了，它对我来说没什么意义。
Once it passed I didn't look at it much again, it didn't appear much to me.
Una vez que pasó no lo volví a mirar mucho, no me apareció mucho.
赛后我想是的，但是……
I think after the game yes, but...
Creo que después del partido sí, pero...
但现在没有那么多了，除了出现在某些社交网络或其他东西上的视频，但是......
But now not so much, except for a video that appears there on some social network or something, but...
Pero ahora no tanto, salvo algún vídeo que te aparezca ahí en alguna red social o algo, sino...
如果没有，那就不多了，但显然每次它出现或你看到它时它都是......
If not, not much more, but obviously every time it appears or you see it it's...
Si no, no mucho más, pero obviamente que cada vez que aparece o lo ves es...
这是非常令人感动的，而且非常美丽。
It is very emotional and very beautiful to see.
Es muy emotivo y muy lindo para ver.
每次看到都觉得更可爱。
Every time you see it it seems cuter.
Cada vez que se ve parece más lindo.
是的，时间越来越长，所以就像......
Yes, more and more time is passing, so it's like...
Sí, además va pasando cada vez más el tiempo, entonces como que...
还有更多的忧郁，但嘿，事实是，这是一个值得享受的美好时刻。
There is more melancholy, but hey, the truth is that it is a nice moment to enjoy.
se agarra más melancolía, pero bueno, la verdad que sí es un lindo momento para disfrutar.
为什么在政变的那一刻做出决定？
Why did you decide at the moment of the coup?
¿Por qué decidiste en el momento del golpe?
我不明白你怎么这么快。
I don't understand how you were so fast.
No entiendo cómo fuiste tan rápido.
10秒内给他在场右侧传球拥抱梅西。
Give him a pass on the right side of the field to hug Messi in 10 seconds.
Dale un pase sobre la parte derecha de la cancha a llegar a abrazar a Messi en 10 segundos.
嗯，因为我认为发生的事情，显然是在利奥受伤之后发生的，这是我们的......
Well, because I think that what was happening, obviously after Leo's injury, which is ours...
Bueno, porque creo que lo que se estaba viviendo, obviamente después de la lesión de Leo, que es nuestro...
我们的队长的标志，他总是想在球场上，不幸的是
emblem of our captain who always wants to be on the field and well unfortunately
emblema nuestro capitán que siempre quiere estar en la cancha y bueno lamentablemente
由于脚踝受伤，我无法继续前进，我们喜欢......
With the ankle I couldn't continue any further and we like...
con lo del tobillo no podía seguir más y nosotros como...
作为同事、朋友，看到他受这样的苦，显然不太好。
As a colleague, friends, seeing him suffer like this is obviously not nice.
Como compañero, amigos, verlo así sufrir obviamente que no es lindo.
好吧，我告诉你，当进球进球时，我想到的第一件事就是去拥抱他，因为显然
And well, I'm telling you, when the goal was scored, the first thing that occurred to me was to go hug him because obviously
Y bueno, ya te digo, cuando fue el gol lo primero que se me ocurrió es ir a abrazarlo a él porque obviamente
从外部来看，你遭受的痛苦要多得多。
From the outside you suffer much more.
Desde afuera se sufre mucho más.
我认为他也比任何人都应得的。
and I think he also deserved it more than anyone.
y creo que él también se lo merecía más que nadie.
看到他哭得那么痛苦，我第一个想到的就是去拥抱他。
The first thing that came to my mind after seeing him cry and suffer like that is to go hug him.
Lo primero que se me vino a la cabeza después de verlo llorar y sufrir así es ir a abrazarlo a él.
显然，在那一刻将进球献给了他。
and obviously to dedicate the goal to him at that moment.
y obviamente que dedicarle el gol a él en ese momento.
当你的妻子、你的小女儿、你的家人、你在体育场的朋友进来时
When your wife, your little daughter, your family, your friends who were in the stadium come in
Cuando entra tu mujer, tu pequeña hija, tu familia, tus amigos que estaban en el estadio
你对他说过的最糟糕的话是什么，或者你们对彼此说过的最糟糕的话是什么？
What was the worst thing you said to him or what was the worst thing you said to each other?
¿Qué fue lo peor que le dijiste o qué fue lo peor que se dijeron?
不，多么可笑，多么可笑。
No, how funny, how funny.
No, qué gracia, qué gracia.
正如我所说，感谢您一如既往的无条件支持。
Thank you for your unconditional support as always, as I say.
Gracias por el aguante incondicional de siempre, como te digo.
有美好的时刻，也有糟糕的时刻，我认为那些时刻是如此美丽
There are good moments, bad moments and I think those moments are so beautiful
Hay momentos buenos, momentos malos y creo que esos momentos tan lindos
它们是与您所爱的人一起享受的。
They are to enjoy with your loved ones.
son para disfrutar con tus seres queridos.
还有这个杯赛的不同之处，回到你之前问我的问题，现在是......
Also what was different about this Cup, going back to what you asked me before, is that now it...
También lo que tuvo diferente esta Copa, volviendo a lo que me preguntabas antes, es que ahora lo...
我们可以和人民、教区、家人一起享受它。
We could enjoy it with the people, the Dioceno, the family.
Lo podíamos disfrutar con la gente, la Dioceno, la familia.
所以我认为这也让它变得非常特别。
So I think that also made it very special.
Entonces creo que eso también lo hizo muy especial.
巴西的家人、亲人都无法陪伴我们。
that out there, what was in Brazil, the family, the loved ones could not accompany us.
que por ahí, lo que fue en Brasil, la familia, los seres queridos no pudieron acompañarnos.
现在，是的，他们整个杯赛都在受苦，所以，我认为那一刻也是对他们的感激之情。
And now yes, they were there suffering the entire Cup, so well, I think that moment is also one of gratitude for them.
Y ahora sí, estuvieron toda la Copa ahí sufriendo, entonces bueno, creo que ese momento también es de agradecimiento para ellos.
杯赛结束后，你在罗萨里奥与你的家人和朋友一起度过了大约 15 天的假期。
You spent almost 15 days or so after the Cup on vacation in Rosario with your people, with your friends.
Estuviste casi 15 días más o menos después de la Copa de vacaciones en Rosario con tu gente, con tus amigos.
我看见你上来了...
I saw you went up...
Vi que subiste...
你给我们烧烤，你去钓鱼，你在喝点小酒。
that you gave us a barbecue, that you went fishing, that you were making a break drink.
que nos metiste un asado, que te fuiste a pescar, que estuviste haciendo bebida de descanso.
但我要问你的是
But what I'm asking you is,
Pero lo que te pregunto es,
当兴奋过去时，你的朋友告诉你什么？
What did your friends tell you when the euphoria passed?
¿Qué te dijeron tus amigos ya cuando pasó la euforia?
罗萨里奥街上的人们对你说了什么？
What did the people on the street in Rosario say to you?
¿Qué te decía la gente en la calle en el Rosario?
不，没什么，显然，我有样品。
No, nothing, obviously, I had samples.
No, nada, obviamente, que tuve muestras.
出于爱意，出于感恩。
of affection, of gratitude.
de cariño, de agradecimiento.
我认为人们是非常感恩的。
I think people are very grateful.
Creo que la gente está muy agradecida.
是什么造就了这一切选择，所有的欢乐……
with what made all this selection, all the joys that...
con lo que hizo toda esta selección, todas las alegrías que...
我告诉人们，他们感到非常认同，所以他们感恩的就是这一点。
Let me tell people, they feel very identified, so what they are grateful for is that.
que le diga a la gente, se siente muy identificada, entonces lo que te agradece es eso.
世界杯前夕发生在他身上的事情之后。
after what had happened to him in the run-up to the World Cup.
después de lo que le había ocurrido en la previa del mundial.
用什么词来形容您职业生涯中的这个时刻？
What is the word that defines this moment in your career?
¿Cuál es la palabra que define este momento de tu carrera?
复赛。
Rematch.
Revancha.
弹力。
Resilience.
Resiliencia.
你在字典里找到了哪一个？
Which one do you find in your dictionary?
¿Cuál ubicás vos en tu diccionario?
不，我不认为这是某种报复，而是一个新的机会。
No, I don't take it as some kind of revenge, but rather a new opportunity.
No, yo no lo tomo como una especie de revancha, sino una nueva oportunidad.
所发生的事情现在已经成为过去。
What happened is now behind us.
ya lo que pasó quedó atrás.
现在我很享受这份礼物，日复一日，能够赢得胜利。
Now I enjoy this present, the day to day, being able to have won.
Ahora disfruto este presente, el día a día, poder haber ganado.
这支球队再次参加美洲杯，我认为这是独一无二的。
another Copa América with this team, I think it is something unique.
otra Copa América con esta selección, creo que es algo único.
所以就像我常说的，
So like I always say,
Entonces, como siempre digo,
加入阿根廷队是一种特权，所以……
Being in the Argentine team is a privileged place, so...
Estar en la selección argentina es un lugar de privilegio, entonces...
每次我们在那里都非常享受，并且像第一天一样捍卫它。
Every time we are there we enjoy it a lot and we defend it like the first day.
Cada vez que estamos ahí lo disfrutamos mucho y lo defendemos como el primer día.
有句话很流行，事情的发生都是有原因的。
There is a popular saying that things happen for a reason.
Hay un dicho popular que dice que las cosas pasan por algo.
那次受伤对你来说是不幸的，但同时它也让你
That injury was unfortunate for you, but at the same time it allowed you to
te tocó lamentable aquella lesión pero al mismo tiempo eso te permitió
参与并见证您女儿的诞生。
be part and witness the birth of your daughter.
ser parte y presenciar el nacimiento de tu hija.
你是如何经历这个序列的？
How did you experience that sequence?
¿Cómo viviste esa secuencia?
事情的发生都是有原因的。
Things happen for a reason.
Las cosas pasan por algo.
他们希望事情是这样的。
They wanted it to be like that.
Querían que fuera así.
但事实是我很感激，因为我能够经历这一切。
But the truth is that I am very grateful because I was able to experience it all.
pero la verdad que estoy muy agradecido porque lo pude vivir todo.
一切都从内部开始，过程是什么。
Everything from within, what the process was.
Todo desde adentro, lo que fue el proceso.
我没有放下手臂，我一直在等待这一刻。
I never lowered my arms, I was waiting for this moment.
Nunca bajé los brazos, esperaba este momento.
我做了很多工作才能回到那个小组，显然
I worked a lot to be able to be back in that group that obviously
Trabajé mucho para poder volver a estar en ese grupo que obviamente
正如我们常说的，再次来到那里并作为其他人之一参加比赛的门槛非常高。
As we always say, the bar is very high and to be there again and compete as one of the others.
Como siempre decimos, la vara está muy alta y volver a estar ahí y competir como uno más.
与决赛加冕一样，我认为这是锦上添花。
Crowning it as it was crowned with the final, I think it was the icing on the cake.
Coronarlo como se coronó con la final, creo que fue la frutilla al postre.
那个神奇的时刻是什么样的？
What was that magical moment like?
¿Cómo fue aquel momento mágico?
因为就像你生命中的一切一样，我指的是你女儿出生的神奇时刻，因为就像你生命中的一切一样，它必须做
because like everything in your life, I mean a magical moment of birth of your daughter, because like everything in your life it has to do
porque como todo en tu vida, me refiero a un momento mágico de nacimiento de tu hija, porque como todo en tu vida tiene que ver
一场足球比赛，因为显然你正在观看与墨西哥的比赛，发生了什么？
with a soccer game, because clearly you were watching the game with Mexico and what happened?
con un partido de fútbol, porque claramente estabas viendo el partido con México y ¿qué pasó?
正是在与墨西哥的比赛中，里奥的进球，我妻子羊水破了，我们就离开了那里。
It was there with the game with Mexico, with Leo's goal, that my wife's water broke and we left from there.
Fue ahí con el partido con México, con el gol de Leo, que mi mujer rompió bolsa y de ahí nos fuimos.
到了医院，我们在车上看到了恩佐的进球。
to the hospital and we saw Enzo's goal from the car.
al hospital y el gol de Enzo lo vimos desde el auto.
显然，从外部来看，人们遭受的痛苦要多得多。
and obviously from the outside one suffers much more.
y obviamente que desde afuera se sufre mucho más.
但是，我确信，有了这群球员
But well, I was convinced that with the group of players
Pero bueno, yo estaba convencido que con el grupo de jugadores
我们有过，我想我们可以继续前进，然后是的，当我能够陪伴他们时
that we had, I think we could move forward and then yes, when I was able to accompany them
que teníamos, creo que se podía sacar adelante y ya después sí, cuando pude acompañarlos
从内部私下里支持他们，事实是
there from within in privacy support them and well the truth is that
ahí desde adentro en la intimidad apoyarlos y bueno la verdad que
能够和他们在一起真是太好了。
It was very nice to be able to be there with them.
Fue muy lindo poder estar ahí con ellos.
所以...
So...
Así que...
所以没什么，事实是我非常感激。
So nothing, the truth is that I am very grateful.
Así que nada, la verdad que muy agradecido.
当你和玛吉谈论那一刻时
When you talk to Maggie about that moment,
Cuando hablás con Maggie de aquel momento,
你还记得什么？
What do you remember?
¿Qué recordás?
你脑子里在想什么？
What's going through your head?
¿Qué es lo que te pasa por la cabeza?
但？
But?
Sí, ¿no?
出生那天是的，显然。
On the day of birth yes, obviously.
Al día de nacimiento sí, obviamente.
一种完全的情感，那一刻是什么。
A total emotion, what that moment was.
Una emoción total, lo que fue ese momento.
他们告诉你，他们告诉你，但你永远想象不到那是什么。
They tell you, they tell you, but you never imagine what it is.
Te dicen, te dicen, pero nunca te imaginas lo que es.
直到你进去为止。
until you're in there.
hasta que estás ahí adentro.
所以没什么，显然这将是一个......
So nothing, obviously it's going to be a moment that...
Así que nada, obviamente que va a ser un momento que...
这将持续一生，而且，又是人生一课。
that will last a lifetime and well, one more life lesson.
que va a quedar para toda la vida y bueno, un aprendizaje más de vida.
艾米莉亚出生了，几天后你......
Emilia was born and a few days later you were...
Nació Emilia y a los pocos días fuiste...
你去卡塔尔是为了靠近你的队友。
You went to Qatar to be close to your teammates.
Te fuiste a Qatar para estar cerca de tus compañeros.
你是怎么生活的？
How did you live it?
¿Cómo lo viviste?
当你知道自己只能欢呼而不能比赛时，你是如何应对的？
How did you handle knowing you could only cheer and not play?
¿Cómo manejaste saber que solo podías alentar y no jugar?
从外面来的人遭受的痛苦要多得多。
that from the outside one suffers much more.
que desde afuera se sufre mucho más.
当你在里面时，你在那个泡沫中，你在另一个泡沫中，但是......
There when you are inside, you are in that bubble, there you are in another but...
Por ahí cuando estás adentro, estás en esa burbuja, por ahí estás en otra pero...
从外面看，你受的苦要多得多，因为你整天都在看电视。
From the outside you suffer much more because you are watching television all day.
Desde afuera se sufre mucho más porque estás todo el día viendo la televisión.
然后它会变得更长。
Then it gets much longer.
Entonces se hace mucho más largo.
但是，显然我的女儿出生后，我最想要的就是和我的同学在一起。
But well, after obviously my daughter was born, what I wanted most was to be with my classmates.
Pero bueno, después obviamente que nació mi hija, lo que más quería era estar con mis compañeros.
就在附近陪伴他们，尽管……
be there accompanying them from close by, although...
estar ahí acompañándolos desde cerca, si bien...
我一直与他们保持联系，我想在那里。
I was in constant contact with them, I wanted to be there.
Estaba en contacto permanente con ellos, quería estar ahí.
陪伴他。
accompany him.
acompañarlo.
幸运的是，一切皆有可能。
So luckily everything was possible.
Así que por suerte se pudo dar todo.
您对卡斯塔雷斯重返奥运有何感受？
How did you experience the Olympic return in Castares?
¿Cómo viviste la vuelta olímpica en Castares?
你是一种词，我们已经谈过一点了，但我想那种情感一定是……
You are a type of words, we have already talked about it a little, but I imagine that the emotion must be...
sos un tipo de palabras, ya lo hemos hablado un poco, pero imagino que la emoción debe ser...
是的，事实是，这非常令人兴奋......
Yes, the truth is that it is very exciting what...
Sí, la verdad que es muy emocionante lo que...
里面所经历的事情是令人费解的。
What was experienced inside was something inexplicable.
Lo que se vivió ahí adentro fue algo inexplicable.
和我的同伴一起经历所有人所遭受的一切。
and being there with my companions experiencing everything that was suffered for all the people.
y estar ahí con mis compañeros viviéndolo todo lo que se sufrió para toda la gente.
在阿根廷，家人、朋友也是如此。
In Argentina too, family, friends.
en Argentina también, la familia, los amigos.
正如我所说，我认为这是独特而美好的东西。
I think it was something unique and good, like I said.
Creo que fue algo único y bueno, como dije.
始终感谢所有人，感谢球员，感谢教练组。
Always grateful to everyone, to the players, to the coaching staff.
Siempre agradecido a todos, a los jugadores, al cuerpo técnico.
感谢总统让我住在那里并陪伴他们。
to the president for letting me live from there and accompany them there.
al presidente por dejármelo vivir desde ahí adentro y estar acompañándolos ahí.
所有那些日子。
all those days.
todos esos días.
正如我告诉你的，我经常阅读你的故事并观看视频。
As I told you, I was reading your story a lot and watching videos.
Como te comenté estuve leyendo bastante tu historia y viendo videos.
在我观察到的最引起我注意的事情中，
And of the things that caught my attention the most, that I observed,
Y de las cosas que más me llamó la atención, que observé,
这是你的朋友罗德里戈·德·保罗在接受索菲·马丁内斯采访时说的。
It was to your friend Rodrigo de Paul, in an interview he did with Sofi Martínez.
Fue a tu amigo Rodrigo de Paul, en una entrevista que hizo con Sofi Martínez.
当谈到他的经历时，他崩溃了。
who broke down when talking about what he had experienced.
que se quebró al hablar de lo que había vivido.
谁说他不知道当你和他们在一起时，他是如何克服痛苦而情绪如此良好的。
who said that he didn't know how he had managed the pain to be so emotionally well when you were with them.
que decía que no sabía cómo había gestionado el dolor como para estar tan bien anímicamente cuando estabas con ellos
你是怎么做到的？
How did you do it?
¿Cómo hiciste?
嗯，我想和罗德里...
Well, I think with Rodri...
Bueno, creo que con Rodri...
虽然我有一种独特的关系，但我认为在世界杯上也是如此
Although I have a unique relationship, I think that also in the World Cup
Si bien tengo una relación única, creo que también en el Mundial
因为我们交谈，所以我们非常团结。
We were very united because we talked.
Nos unió mucho porque hablábamos.
每天我都会在比赛前给他写信，然后是比赛，他怎么样，然后……
Every day, I wrote to him before the games, then the games, how he was, then...
todos los días, yo le escribía antes los partidos, después los partidos, cómo estaba, entonces...
嗯，我认为我们非常接近。
Well, I think we were very close.
Bueno, creo que estuvimos muy pegados.
也是因为世界杯。
Because of the World Cup too.
Debido al Mundial también.
但好吧，是的，这就是他和我所说的。
But well, yes, there's what he said and me.
Pero bueno, sí, por ahí lo que dijo y yo.
我告诉他的是，发生的事情已经发生了，我正在看着
a little what I was telling him was that what had happened had already happened that I was looking at
un poco lo que le decía era eso que ya lo que había pasado pasó que yo miraba
前进，显然他们给了我必要的力量
forward, that obviously they gave me the necessary strength to
para adelante, que obviamente ellos me dieron la fuerza necesaria como para
跟随并陪伴他们，让他在附近让我
to also follow and accompany them and having him there nearby made me
para seguir también y acompañarlos y tenerlo ahí cerca me hizo
这对我来说非常好，他们让我感觉自己是其中的一部分。
It was very good for me, they made me feel part of it.
Me hizo muy bien, me hicieron sentir parte.
从第一天起，我就非常感激。
from the first day, so the truth is that I am very grateful.
desde el primer día, así que la verdad que muy agradecido.
最让你兴奋的是队形中的塔特尔。
The thing that excited you the most was that tartel in the formation.
La cosa que más te emocionaron fue aquel tartel en la formación.
我在家看比赛，没想到会这样。
I was watching the game at home and I never imagined it.
Yo estaba viendo el partido en casa y nunca me imaginé.
那样的事情可能会发生，而且很好。
that something like that could happen and good.
que podía pasar algo así y bueno.
当他们出现在球场上时，我看到了那个标志，这让我非常兴奋。
When they came out on the field, I saw that sign, it made me very excited.
Ya cuando salieron a la cancha, vi el cartel ese, me hizo emocionar mucho.
我当时就说，妈的，我一定是做了什么正确的事，他们才带着那个牌子去看比赛。
And there I said, shit, I must have done something right for them to go out to the game with that sign.
Y ahí dije, mierda che, algo habré hecho bien como para que salgan al partido con ese cartel.
所以我认为这也是推动......
So I think that was also a push for...
Entonces creo que eso también fue un empujón para...
显然，这是一个让我很充实的举动。
to get ahead and obviously it was a gesture that filled me a lot.
para salir adelante y obviamente que fue un gesto que me llenó y mucho.
我想这会让你感到满足，你做了一些事情，我一定说得很好，不仅是从足球方面，因为这谈到了......
I imagine that this fulfills you, that you did something, I must have said well, not only from the football side, because that speaks of...
Imagino que eso te llena, que hiciste algo, debo haber dicho bien, no solamente desde los futbolísticos, porque eso habla de...
您与所有同事的工会以及与其中一些人的友谊关系。
of the union you have with all your colleagues and with some of them a friendship relationship.
de la unión que tenés con todos tus compañeros y con alguno de ellos una relación de amistad.
是的，是的，但是当我告诉你一些我做得很好的事情时，我是从……
Yes, yes, but when I tell you something I have done well, I speak from...
Sí, sí, pero ya cuando te digo algo habré hecho bien hablo desde...
人类，个人，已经把它抛在了外面。
the human, the personal, already leaving it outside.
lo humano, lo personal, ya dejándolo afuera.
足球，因为这样的举动并不是每天都会发生，而且所有这些人
football because a gesture like that doesn't happen every day and all those people
lo futbolístico porque un gesto así no pasan todos los días y todas esas personas
把你记在心里。
Keep you in mind.
Te tengan presente.
所以，是的，那一刻对我来说非常激动，非常特别。
So yes, that moment for me was very emotional, very special.
Así que sí, ese momento para mí fue muy emotivo, muy especial.
这是一种情感上的推动，然后是接受。
which was a emotional push and then receiving.
que fue un empujón anímico y después recibir.
我的伴侣发来的信息以及一切，事实是，这非常好。
the messages from my partner and everything, the truth is that it was very nice.
los mensajes de mi compañero y todo, la verdad que fue muy lindo.
而潜藏的就是你的毅力、你的韧性。
and what is latent is your perseverance, your resilience.
y lo que está latente es tu perseverancia, tu resiliencia.
您作为重要循环之一开始了阶梯循环，六年后您仍然具有相同的地位。
You started the step cycle as one of the essential ones and six years later you still have the same status.
arrancaste el ciclo escalónico como uno de los indispensables y seis años después seguís teniendo el mismo estatus.
你是做了什么，才能在国家队六年不间断地有这样的发展？
What did you do to be able to have this development in the National Team for six years uninterruptedly?
¿Qué hiciste para poder tener este desarrollo en la Selección durante seis años de manera ininterrumpida?
我认为显然在这些过程中
I think that obviously in these processes
Creo que obviamente en estos procesos
所以最重要的是不要放松。
So the most important thing is not to relax.
Así lo más importante es no relajarte.
显然，循环...
Obviously the cycle of...
Obviamente que el ciclo de...
Leo Scaloni 非常成功，但同时这并不容易，我们开始了
by Leo Scaloni was very successful, but well, at the same time it was not easy, we started
de Leo Scaloni fue muy exitoso, pero bueno, a su vez no fue fácil, arrancamos
有了这种友好的事情，我们不知道会发生什么，是否会继续，是否不会继续。
With that friendly thing, we didn't know what was going to happen, if it was going to continue, if it wasn't going to continue.
Con eso amistoso, que no sabíamos qué iba a pasar, si iba a seguir, si no iba a seguir.
他说他总是很清楚
and he always had it very clear, he said
y él siempre lo tuvo muy claro, él dijo
直到他来到这里的那一天，球员们都希望他们为他、为他们所代表的球衣付出一切。
that until the day he is here, that the players wanted them to give their all for him, for the shirt they represent.
que hasta el día que él esté, que los jugadores querían que den el máximo por él, por la camiseta que representan.
那么，好吧。
So, well.
Entonces, bueno.
我认为团队开始变得非常团结，我认为后来
I think that there began to be a very nice group unity and I think that later
Creo que se empezó ahí a haber una unión de grupo muy linda y creo que después
这就是所发生的一切的结果。
That was the result of everything that came.
Eso fue el resultado de todo lo que vino.
但是嘿，如果有什么...
But hey, if there is something that...
Pero bueno, si hay algo que...
可以说的是，你在那个地方永远不能放松，因为
What one can say is that you can never relax in that place because
que uno puede decir es que no te puede relajar nunca en ese lugar porque
门槛非常高，他代表阿根廷队，这是所有阿根廷人的梦想......
The bar is very high, he is representing the Argentine team, the dream of all the people who...
La barra está muy alta, está representando a la selección argentina, al sueño de todas las personas que...
如果你想成为足球运动员，那么这里就是一个地方
who want to be soccer players, then it is a place
que quieren ser jugadores de fútbol, entonces es un lugar
非常好，但同时也有很多责任。
very nice but at the same time with a lot of responsibility.
muy lindo pero a su vez con mucha responsabilidad.
所以没什么，总是继续走同一条道路，工作，谦虚。
So nothing, always continue on the same path, of work, of humility.
Entonces nada, siempre seguir por el mismo camino, del trabajo, de la humildad.
成长、学习、向最伟大的人学习、倾听。
of growth, of learning, learning from the greatest, listening.
de crecimiento, de aprender, aprender de lo más grande, escuchar.
因为我们在那里有很好的参考资料，并且有人试图
because we have great references there and well one tries to
porque tenemos grandes referentes ahí y bueno uno trata de
学习很多东西，倾听，显然，从这里得到的就是继续沿着同样的道路前进。
to learn a lot, to listen and obviously what comes from here is to continue along the same path.
de aprender mucho, de escuchar y obviamente de acá lo que viene es seguir por el mismo camino.
2018年，当这群年轻人带着临时教练开始想象时，同样困难的是
It was equally difficult in 2018 when that group of young people started with an interim coach to imagine that
Era difícil igual en aquel 2018 cuando arrancó ese grupo de jóvenes con un técnico interino imaginar que
六年后，我们将谈论美洲锦标赛、世界冠军、决赛冠军。
Six years later we will be talking about the American Championship, World Champion, Champion of the very final.
Seis años después vamos a estar hablando del Campeonato de América, Campeón del Mundo, Campeón de la finalísima.
如果你想象得到，你就是一个现象。
If you imagined it, you are a phenomenon.
Si vos lo imaginabas, sos un fenómeno.
我想你连想象都没有想到，对吧？
I don't think you even imagined it, right?
Yo creo que no lo imaginaban ni ustedes, ¿no?
不不不，显然人们不是这么想的。
No, no, obviously one didn't imagine it like that.
No, no, obviamente que uno no lo imaginaba así.
但是，正如我告诉过你的，当利奥到达时，会谈的内容是我不知道我会在那里呆多久。
But well, as I told you, when Leo arrived the talks were about I don't know how long I'll be there.
Pero bueno, como te dije, cuando llegó Leo las charlas eran yo no sé hasta cuándo voy a estar.
但是，嘿，在那一天之前我会付出一切。
But hey, until that day I'm going to give everything.
Pero bueno, hasta el día que esté voy a dar todo.
我对你也有同样的期望。
I expect the same from you.
Espero de ustedes lo mismo.
嗯，我认为有点像那样。
And well, I think it was a bit like that.
Y bueno, creo que fue un poco eso.
给予，给予。
Give and give.
Dar y dar.
我认为团体团结就在那里开始形成。
And there I think that group unity began to be created.
Y ahí creo que se empezó a crear esa unión de grupo.
很好的是，正是它最终让你走到了这一步，让你看到了这一点
It's good that it was ultimately what took you so far that you see that
que bueno que fue en definitiva lo que lo que te llevó tan lejos que vos vea que
然后你的伴侣跳到你身上。
and your partner jumps on you.
y tu compañero se te tira de cabeza.
在球场上，训练中没有一天是放松的。
on the court, that in training there is not a day that anyone relaxes.
en la cancha, que en el entrenamiento no hay un día que ninguno se relaje.
我认为这一切都使得...
I think all of that made...
Creo que todo eso hizo que...
让我们走得更远，实现这个团队所取得的成就。
Let's go far and achieve what this team achieved.
que se llegue lejos y a conseguir lo que consiguió esta selección.
当你开始踢球时，首先轮到孩子们，然后轮到年轻球员们。
First it was the kid's turn when you started kicking the ball, then it was the younger players' turn.
Primero tocó de pibe cuando empezabas a patear la pelota, después tocó de jugadores inferiores.
然后轮到你成为职业选手了，然后你就成为了 2018 年团队的一员。
Then it was your turn as a professional and then you were part of the 2018 team.
Después te tocó como profesional y después fuiste parte de la selección del 2018.
这个团体有什么？
What does this group have?
¿Qué tiene este grupo?
已进入历史。
to have entered history.
para haber entrado en la historia.
与选择的关系是......
The relationship with the selection was...
La relación con la selección fue...
这是很独特的，因为在年轻的时候我从来没有必要去青年队。
It was something unique because in youth I never had to go to youth teams.
Fue algo único porque yo en juveniles no me tocó ir nunca a selecciones juveniles.
我第一次必须去的是...
The first time I had to go was...
La primera vez que me tocó ir fue...
那是我成为奥运会核心的时候。
It was when I was central to the Olympic Games.
fue cuando estaba en central a los Juegos Olímpicos.
那个电话后来把我卖到了巴黎。
that call that later sold me to Paris.
ese llamado que después a mí me venden al París.
所以我第一次踏上球场是为了备战奥运会。
So the first time I set foot on the grounds was to prepare for the Olympic Games.
Entonces la primera vez que yo pisaba el predio era para prepararme para unos Juegos Olímpicos.
所以它已经创建了......
So there it was already created...
Entonces ahí ya se gestó...
一些独特的东西开始形成，因为最重要的是他们不向玩家授予许可。
Something unique began to take shape because on top of that they were giving permission not to the players.
Se empezó a gestar algo único porque encima estaban con que le daban permiso no a los jugadores.
好吧，从那里开始发生的一切都令人难以置信。
And well, from there everything that came was incredible.
Y bueno, a partir de ahí todo lo que vino fue increíble.
这也是国家队的第一次征召。
The first call to the Senior National Team as well.
El primer llamado a la Selección Mayor también.
我记得
I remember that
me acuerdo que
这是非常激动人心的，后来他们确实很享受，伟大的球员都经过这里。
It was very emotional and afterwards they did enjoy it, great players passed by here.
que fue muy emotivo y ya después sí disfrutaron, pasaron grandísimos jugadores por acá.
正如我告诉过你的，它们将继续发生。
and they will continue to happen, as I told you.
y van a seguir pasando, como te dije.
大多数梦想踢足球的球员都梦想为阿根廷国家队效力。
Most players who dream of playing soccer dream of playing for the Argentine national team.
La mayoría de los jugadores que sueñan con jugar al fútbol sueñan con jugar en la selección argentina.
因此，能够处于这样一个优越的位置真是太好了。
So being in a privileged place like that is very nice.
Entonces estar en un lugar de privilegio así es muy lindo.
显然，正如我告诉你的，它伴随着许多责任。
And obviously, as I told you, it comes with many responsibilities.
Y obviamente, como te dije, es de muchas responsabilidades.
你认为这个团队有什么是以前的团队所没有的？
And what do you think this group had that the previous ones couldn't have?
¿Y qué crees que tuvo este grupo que no pudieron tener los anteriores?
你只是参与了前面一个很短的过程，你就到达了终点。
You just participated in a very short previous process, you reached the end.
Justamente participaste de un proceso anterior muy cortito, llegaste al final.
你认为这个群体有什么是其他人所没有的？
What do you think this group had that the others couldn't have?
¿Qué crees que tuvo este grupo que no lo pudieron tener los otros?
在那些重要的时刻，那份幸运，因为请注意……
that there in those moments of size, that share of luck, because notice that...
que por ahí en esos momentos de talle, esa cuota de suerte, porque fíjate que...
他们在决赛中输掉了点球大战。
that they lost finals playing better on penalties.
que se perdieron finales jugando mejor por penales.
所以，最终，
So, ultimately,
Entonces, en definitiva,
这项运动总是充满运气。
There is always that amount of luck in this sport.
Siempre en este deporte hay esa cuota de suerte.
它是给这一窝的，但是，我想……
It was given to this litter, but well, I think...
se le dio a esta camada, pero bueno, yo creo que...
前几层和所有通过的球员都为阿根廷队定位。
The previous layers and all the players who passed positioned the Argentine team.
Las camadas anteriores y todos los jugadores que pasaron posicionaron a la selección argentina.
总是在那里，因为看看所有来自......的球员
Always up there because look at all the players who went from...
Siempre ahí arriba porque fíjate todos los jugadores que pasaron de...
拥有丰富的经验，很多层次结构，所以，这是一个
with a lot of experience, a lot of hierarchy, so well, it's a
de mucha trayectoria, mucha jerarquía, entonces bueno, es un
这对每个人来说都是一个享受的时刻。
It is a moment of enjoyment for everyone.
Es un momento de disfrute para todos.
2018年我们都以为你会上场，但你没有上场时间
In 2018 we all thought you were going to play, you didn't have minutes to play
en un del 2018 todos pensábamos que ibas a jugar, no te tocó tener minutos para jugar
今天从远处看是什么造就了你。
from a distance today what generates you.
a la distancia hoy lo que te genera vos.
把一切都当作学习经历。
Take everything as a learning experience.
Tomar todo como un aprendizaje.
虽然当时我已经踢了世界杯前的友谊赛，然后就不用踢了。
Although at that time I had played the friendlies before the World Cup and then I didn't have to play.
Si bien en ese momento me había tocado jugar los amistosos previo al Mundial y después no me tocó jugar.
我把它当作一次学习经历。
I took it as a learning experience.
Lo tomé como un aprendizaje.
作为现在没有触动我的事情，以后一定会发生，继续努力，不要放弃。
As something that didn't touch me now, it will have to happen later, keep working, not give up.
como algo que no me tocó ahora, tendrá que ser más adelante, seguir trabajando, no echar la cabeza.
我们知道实现这一目标并不容易。
We know that things to achieve it are not going to be easy.
Sabemos que las cosas para conseguirla no van a ser fáciles.
那么好吧，我想我也不能拥有
So well, I think that I also couldn't have
Entonces bueno, creo que también no haber podido
我认为在那届世界杯上踢了几分钟帮助我说得很好。
I think playing a few minutes in that World Cup helped me say well.
Disputar algún minuto en ese mundial creo que me sirvió para decir bueno.
为了一些令人兴奋的事情，我必须加倍努力工作，加倍努力训练。
I have to work twice as hard, I have to train twice as hard for something exciting.
Tengo que trabajar el doble, tengo que entrenarme el doble por algo abrazido.
并且始终保持不放弃、不断尝试的心态。
and always with that mentality of not giving up, of keeping trying.
y siempre con esa mentalidad de no bajar los brazos, de seguir intentándolo.
好吧，最终它得到了回报。
And well, in the end it was rewarded.
Y bueno, al final tuvo recompensa.
当你回顾过去时，四岁时在圣何塞踢球的孩子吉奥会说什么？
When you look back a little, what does the kid Gio who played in San José when he was four years old say?
Cuando mirás un poquito para atrás, ¿qué le dice el pibe Gio que jugaba en San José a los cuatro años?
今天给男孩爸爸吗？
to the boy today dad?
al chico hoy papá?
不，我想我总是
No, I think I always
No, creo que siempre me
我遵循同样的路线，享受每一刻。
I followed the same line, to enjoy every moment.
Me guié por la misma línea, de disfrutar cada momento.
因为嗯，简而言之，一个人正在做一个从小就梦想的事情，但很多次......
Because well, in short one is doing what one has dreamed of since childhood but many times...
Porque bueno, en definitiva uno está haciendo lo que soñó desde chico pero muchas veces...
可以给你也可以不给你。
It can be given to you or not.
se te puede dar como no.
所以我认为生活这一切......
So I think that living all this...
Entonces creo que estar viviendo todo esto...
这已经是一件不可思议的事情了。
It's already something incredible.
ya es algo increíble.
好吧，就像我告诉你的那样，我享受每一天，我享受每一次训练，我热爱我所做的事情。
So well, like I told you, I enjoy every day, I enjoy every training, I love what I do.
Entonces bueno, como te dije, disfruto cada día, disfruto cada entrenamiento, amo lo que hago.
虽然我们有很多责任，很多压力，但你不会停止做你喜欢的事情。
Although we have many responsibilities, many pressures, you will not stop doing what you like.
Si bien tenemos muchas responsabilidades, muchas presiones, no dejarás de hacer lo que te gusta.
所以，好吧，我们知道它也过得很快，因为，看，我们正在谈论
So, well, we know it goes by quickly too because, look, we're talking
Entonces, bueno, sabemos que también se pasa rápido porque, fíjate, estamos hablando
2018年世界杯，六年过去了，距离我代表国家队出道已经七年了。
2018 World Cup, six years have passed, seven years since I debuted with the national team.
Mundial 2018, ya pasaron seis años, siete años que debuté con la selección.
好吧，时间过去了，显然你留下的就是这些时刻。
So well, time passes and obviously what you have left are these moments.
Entonces bueno, el tiempo pasa y obviamente lo que te quedan son estos momentos.
与此同时，我将享受这条路。
In the meantime I'm going to enjoy the road.
Mientras tanto voy a disfrutar el camino.
在你的家庭记忆的后备箱里有一张非常特别的照片，你小时候，你有
In the trunk of your family memories there is a very special photo, you were little, you had
En el baúl de los recuerdos de tu familia hay una foto muy especial, vos eras chiquitito tenías
七年了，我记得差不多吧，你是中央的吉祥物。
7 years, I remember correctly, more or less, and you were Central's mascot.
7 años, yo no recuerdo mal, más o menos, y fuiste mascota de Central.
怎么样？
How was that?
¿Cómo fue eso?
是的，是的，作为一名球迷，我喜欢和球员们一起出去玩
Yes, yes, being a fan I loved hanging out with the players whenever
Sí, sí, yo al ser hincha me encantaba salir con los jugadores en el momento que
什么是可能的以及何时实现的。
what was possible and when it was achieved.
que se podía y cuando se conseguía.
是的，它触动了我。
And yes, it touched me.
Y sí, me tocó.
我不得不作为宠物出去。
I had to go out there as a pet.
Me tocó salir ahí de mascota.
我还保存着一张照片。
I have a photo still saved.
Tengo una foto todavía guardada.
但他就在坎波拉小狗旁边。
but he was next to the Cámpora puppy.
pero estaba al lado del cachorro Cámpora.
所以是的，我经历了整个宠物过程，之后......
So yeah, I went through that whole pet process, after...
Así que sí, pasé todo ese proceso de mascota, después de...
对他来说已经足够了，所有的流程我都经历过了。
It's enough for him, I went through all the processes.
Le alcanza pelota, pasé por todos los procesos.
你花了多少钱才到达第一个？
How much did it cost you to get to the first one?
¿Cuánto te costó llegar a la primera?
智利切尔西曾效力于美国冠军国家队，效力于欧洲最好的俱乐部，但你花了多长时间？
A Chilero Chelsea who played in the National Team, which was the champion of America, played in the best clubs in Europe, but how long did it take you?
Un Chilero Chelsea que jugaba en la Selección, que era el campeón de América, jugaba en los mejores clubes de Europa, pero ¿cuánto te llevó?
为了这一刻，你花了多长时间、做出了多少牺牲？
How long did it take you and how many sacrifices were there to get to this moment?
¿Cuánto tiempo te llevó y cuántos sacrificios hubo para llegar a este momento?
而且是一生，因为最终一个人会放弃一切来实现在一线队踢球的梦想。
And a lifetime, because ultimately one leaves everything to fulfill the dream of playing in the first team.
Y toda la vida, porque en definitiva uno deja todo para cumplir el sueño de jugar en primera.
一个人四岁就开始踢足球，但是......
One starts playing soccer at the age of four, but...
Uno arranca a los cuatro años a jugar al fútbol, pero...
尽管那一刻你不会考虑这一切，但当你变老时。
Although at that moment you don't think about all this, when you get older.
Si bien en ese momento no piensas todo esto, ya cuando te vas haciendo más grande.
你开始承担更多的责任，因为显然我的梦想是首次亮相并担任第一中后卫。
You start to have more responsibilities, since obviously my dream was to debut and play in the first center back.
empezás a tener más responsabilidades, ya obviamente que mi sueño era debutar y jugar en la primera de central.
好吧，那就是你开始把很多事情放在一边的时候。
So well, that's when you start to leave a lot of things aside.
Entonces bueno, ahí es cuando empezás a dejar un montón de cosas de lado.
因为你已经错过了生日，因为已经有很多事情你不能做，因为……
because you already miss birthdays, because there are already a lot of things that you can't do, because...
porque ya te perdés cumpleaños, porque ya hay un montón de cosas que no lo podés hacer, porque...
所以一切都在你的城市里，当你在很远的地方时我什至不告诉你。
And so everything being in your city, then when you are far away I don't even tell you.
Y así todo estando en tu ciudad, después cuando estás lejos ni te digo.
但是好吧，那一刻人们就已经开始安定下来，开始准备了。
But well, at that moment one already begins to settle one's head, one begins to prepare.
Pero bueno, en ese momento ya uno ya empieza a acomodar la cabeza, empieza a prepararse.
并且永远不要放弃，不要放弃。
And always don't give up, don't give up.
Y siempre no bajar los brazos, no darse por vencido.
当机会到来时，你必须充分利用它们。
When opportunities arrive, you have to take advantage of them.
cuando llegan las oportunidades, hay que aprovecharlas.
在你的青春期，当你第一次取得成绩时，你说你的偶像是玛丽亚，而他们是唯一的……
In your adolescence, when you were giving your first grades, you said that your idol was María and that the only thing they were...
En tu adolescencia, cuando daba tus primeras notas, decías que tu ídolo era la de María y que lo único que eran...
他们的相似之处在于都是左撇子。
They were similar in that they were both left-handed.
que tenían parecido en que los dos eran zurdos.
你是否仍然认为他们唯一的共同点就是都是左撇子？
Do you still think the same thing that the only thing they have in common is that they are both left-handed?
Seguís pensando lo mismo que lo único que tienen parecido es que los dos son zurdos?
是的，是的，我记得有一张纸条说，当我年轻的时候，我...
Yes, yes, I remember a note that when I was younger I...
Sí, sí, me acuerdo de una nota que cuando era más pibe lo...
我说了，但什么也没说，正如我所说，国际棋联显然是为了什么
I said it and nothing, as I said, FIDE obviously for what
lo dije y nada, como dije, FIDE obviamente para lo
对于中央球员来说，因为他从那里出来，看到他在皇家马德里赢得了冠军联赛，在欧洲最好的俱乐部中取得了胜利。
for the central players, because he came out of there and see him at Real Madrid winning the Champions League, triumphing in the best clubs in Europe.
para los jugadores de central, porque él salió de ahí y verlo en el Real Madrid ganando Champions, triunfando en los mejores clubes de Europa.
就像那里的青年队球员一样，他对他进行了很多反思，他想成为像他一样的人。
Like the player there, from the youth team, reflected a lot on him, he wanted to be like him.
como que el jugador de ahí, de inferiores, se reflejaba mucho en él, quería ser como él.
所以我认为所有的垃圾...
So I think that litter all...
Entonces creo que esa camada todos...
作为一名核心球迷并在那里踢球，他们就是这么认为的。
Being a central fan and playing there, they saw it as that.
al ser hincha de central y estar jugando ahí, lo veían como eso.
随后
Afterwards the
Ya después la
生活带我去不同的地方。
Life was taking me to different places.
La vida me fue llevando a lugares diferentes.
我记得有一次他在罗萨里奥度假，我还没有在中央首次亮相，我就去了那所房子。
I remember one time when he was on vacation in Rosario, that I had not yet debuted in central, that I went to the house.
Me acuerdo una vez que él estaba vacación en Rosario, que yo todavía no había debutado en central, que fui a la casa.
直接向他要照片，我发现他在那里，我就回家了。
to ask him directly for a photo and I found out he was there, I went home.
a pedirle una foto directamente y me enteré que estaba ahí, me fui a la casa.
索要照片，然后……
to ask for a photo and then...
a pedir una foto y ya después...
让他成为巴黎的队友，然后建立了关系......
having him as a teammate in Paris and then forming a relationship...
tenerlo como compañero en el París y ya después hacer una relación de...
好吧，我认为这就是生活和足球的美妙之处，以及学习的魅力。
So well, I think that's the beauty of life and football, the learning.
Entonces bueno, creo que eso es lo lindo que tiene la vida y el fútbol, los aprendizajes.
显然它没有屋顶，因为我不得不要一张照片......
and obviously it doesn't have a roof because I had to ask for a photo...
y obviamente que no tiene techo porque de pasar a pedirle una foto...
作为偶像，他将共享烧烤，共享球场。
As an idol he will be sharing a barbecue, sharing a court.
Como ídolo va a estar compartiendo un asado, compartiendo una cancha.
一起赢得奖杯，每天训练，我认为这是非常好的事情。
winning trophies together, training every day, I think it's something very nice.
ganando trofeos juntos, entrenando todos los días, creo que es algo muy lindo.
你还记得那张照片还是不记得？
Do you remember that photo or don't you remember?
¿Se acuerda de esa foto o no se acuerda?
是的，是的。
Yes, yes.
Sí, sí.
是的，是的，直到今天他还记得。
Yes, yes, to this day he remembers.
Sí, sí, hasta el día de hoy se acuerda.
你保存了吗？
Do you have it saved or not?
¿La tenés guardada o no?
是的，是的，我已经保存了，我给你看。
Yes, yes, I have it saved, I'll show it to you.
Sí, sí, la tengo guardada, se la muestro.
好的，很好。
Okay, good.
Vale, bueno.
是的，我告诉他那天他很快就给我打扫干净了。
Yes, I told him that he cleaned me quickly that day.
Sí, le dije que ese día me limpió rápido.
他拍了照片，半是着急，好，好，半是把我们赶出了家门。
He took the photo, he was half in a hurry, well, well, and half kicked us out of the house.
Sacó la foto, estaba medio apurado, bueno, bueno, y medio que nos echó de la casa.
但是，好吧，直到今天我们仍在继续...我们继续他妈的，但是好吧，它也标志着什么...
But well, to this day we continue... we continue fucking with that, but well, there it also marked what...
Pero bueno, hasta el día de hoy seguimos... seguimos jodiendo con eso, pero bueno, ahí también marcaba lo que...
什么是...
what was...
lo que era...
他的谦逊，他作为一名球员和一个人的品质。
his humility, what he was as a player, as a person.
su humildad, lo que era como jugador, como persona.
然后当我到达巴黎时，
And then when I arrived in Paris,
Y después ya cuando llegué a París,
他对我来说就像父亲一样。
He acted as a father to me.
Me hizo de padre.
从第一天起，他就欢迎我，他把我抱起来，他带走了我，他带来了我。
From day one he welcomed me, he picked me up, he took me, he brought me.
Desde el día uno me recibió, me pasaba a buscar, me llevaba, me traía.
当事情进展不顺利时，他会发消息。
He sent messages when things weren't going well.
Mandaba mensajes cuando las cosas no iban bien.
当事情进展顺利时他给我发消息，所以这也是最困难的事情。
He sent me messages when things were going well, so that's the hardest thing too.
Me mandaba mensajes cuando las cosas iban bien, o sea que eso es lo más difícil también.
所以什么也没有，显然他永远感激他所做的一切。
So nothing, obviously eternally grateful for everything he did.
Así que nada, obviamente eternamente agradecido por todo lo que hizo.
那你当时是怎么处理的，特别是刚开始的时候，后来就很正常了？
And how did you manage at that time, especially when you started, afterward it was something normal?
¿Y cómo gestionabas en aquello momento, sobre todo cuando arrancaste, después ya fue algo normal?
你的酒不是你的朋友。
that your wine was not your friend.
que tu vino no fuera tu amigo.
起初这很困难，因为......
And at first it was difficult because...
Y al principio costaba porque...
因为我要告诉你的是...
Because what I'm telling you...
Porque lo que te digo...
我从去博尔达尼奥父母家索要一张照片，到……
I went from going to ask for a photo at my parents' house, in Boldaño, to being...
Pasé de ir a pedirle una foto a la casa de los padres, a Boldaño, a estar...
他们和他一起训练，喝酒。
They are training with him, drinking mate.
Están entrenando con él, tomando mate.
但是，当我作为直接中锋回到巴黎时，这种情况发生在我身上。
But well, that happened to me a little when I went as a direct center back to Paris.
Pero bueno, yo me pasó un poco eso cuando fui de central directo al París.
这让我很震惊，因为数量太多
It kind of shocked me a lot because of the amount of
como que me chocaba mucho por la cantidad de
著名球员和一切，而且更重要的是我。
of renowned players and everything that was, and more than that it was me.
de jugadores que había de renombre y todo lo que era, y más que era mí.
我在欧洲的第一次经历感觉就像在迪士尼。
My first experience in Europe felt like I was at Disney.
Mi primera experiencia en Europa me parecía que estaba en Disney.
我简直不敢相信，每次我来到更衣室换衣服训练时，我都不敢相信。
I couldn't believe it, every time I came to the locker room changing to train, I couldn't believe it.
No lo podía creer, cada vez que llegaba al vestuario cambiándome para entrenar, no lo podía creer.
好吧，一开始显然这对我来说有点困难，但后来......
So well, at first obviously that was a bit difficult for me, but later on...
Entonces bueno, al principio obviamente que me costaba un poco eso, pero ya después lo...
我自然而然地接受了。
I took it naturally.
Lo tomé con naturalidad.
然后当你开始为国家队效力时，人们就会消化甚至说你是最能诠释这一点的人之一
and then when you start playing for the national team it is digested or even said that you are one of the people who best interprets
y después cuando empiezas a jugar en la selección se digiera o se diga todavía que sos una de las personas que mejor interpreta
球场上的梅西。
to Messi on the pitch.
a Messi dentro de la cancha.
这个评论对你产生了什么影响？
What does that comment generate in you?
¿Qué te genera ese comentario?
尽量不要...
try not...
trata de no...
不重视外界所说的话，无论是好话还是坏话。
of not giving importance to what is said outside, whether good or bad things.
de no darle importancia a lo que se diga afuera, sean buenas o cosas malas.
但是，是的，正如我常说的，这是一种自豪和荣幸。
but yes, as I always said, it is a pride and a privilege.
pero sí que, como siempre dije, es un orgullo y es un privilegio.
能够和他一起训练，共享一个球场。
being able to train with him, share a court.
poder entrenar con él, compartir una cancha.
显然，一开始人们也将他视为偶像，视为如此伟大的人物。
Obviously also at the beginning one sees him as an idol, as such a great figure.
Obviamente que también al principio uno lo ve como un ídolo, como una figura tan, tan grande.
这对你来说很难，对你来说很难，你甚至很难看它，你不知道如何......
And it's hard for you, it's hard for you, you even have a hard time looking at it, you don't know how...
Y te cuesta, te cuesta, hasta te da cosa mirarlo, no sabes cómo...
我不知道，所以这是令人难以置信的事情，已经是第一个电话了。
I don't know, so it's something incredible, already the first call.
No sé, entonces es algo increíble, ya la primera convocatoria.
我简直不敢相信我在哪里，在那里训练，然后，好吧，分享球场。
I couldn't believe where I was, training there and then, well, sharing the court.
No podía creer dónde estaba, entrenando ahí y ya después, bueno, compartiendo cancha.
事实上，我很荣幸能够分享
The truth is that I am privileged to have been able to share
La verdad que soy un privilegiado de poder haber compartido
和他在一起的时间很多，比赛很多，美好的时刻很多。
So much time with him, so many games, so many beautiful moments.
Tanto tiempo con él, tantos partidos, tantos lindos momentos.
好吧。
And well.
Y bueno.
那么显然足球和生活稍后会引导你实现这一点......
Then obviously football and life will lead you to that later...
Después obviamente el fútbol y la vida te va llevando a que después ya...
不要只在球场上学习，还要在球场外学习。
Don't just learn on the court, but outside.
No solo aprenda dentro de la cancha, sino afuera.
他是一个多么伟大的人啊，分享一些朋友，一起聊天。
What a great human person he is, sharing some mates, a chat.
lo gran persona humana que es, compartir unos mates, una charla.
人们试图多听多学，但正如我告诉你的，直到今天，人们还没有……
and one tries to listen a lot and learn, but as I tell you, to this day one does not...
y uno trata de escuchar mucho y de aprender, pero como te digo, hasta el día de hoy uno no...
您无法相信这整个过程对您来说是什么样的。
You can't believe what this whole process was like for you.
no puede creer lo que fue viviendo todo este proceso.
你是那个一起去任何地方的团体的一部分。
You are part of that group that goes everywhere together.
Vos sos parte de ese grupo que va para todos lados juntos.
莱安德罗·帕雷德斯·德·波尔
Leandro Paredes de Pol.
奥塔门特·利奥和菲迪奥。
Otamente Leo and Fideo.
Otamente Leo y Fideo.
那个每天都在一起并且基本上很开心的小团体是怎么回事？
What is it about that little group that is together every day and basically has fun?
¿Qué tiene ese grupito que están todos los días juntos y que se ve que se divierten básicamente?
是的，它什么都有一点。
Yes, it has a little bit of everything.
Sí, tiene un poco de todo.
请注意，他们更多...
Notice that they are much more...
Fíjate que ellos son mucho más...
更大，更有经验，只有我们三个人，更多的孩子，更多......
bigger, more experienced and there it was the three of us, more kids, more...
más grande, más experimentado y por ahí nosotros éramos nosotros tres, más pibes, más...
整天到处都是笑话，我们没有让他独自一人，我们没有让他独自一人。
more jokes all day here and there, we didn't leave him alone, we didn't let him be alone.
más jodones todo el día acá para allá, no lo dejábamos tranquilo, no lo dejábamos estar solos nosotros.
我们一起到处搬家。
We moved everywhere together.
Nos movíamos para todos lados juntos.
嗯，我认为已经形成了一个很好的团体，建立了良好的友谊，显然......
And well, I think a nice group was formed, a nice friendship and obviously...
Y bueno, creo que se formó un lindo grupo, una linda amistad y obviamente que...
随着时间的推移，这一点被锻造得更多。
that with the passage of time was forged much more.
que con el correr del tiempo se fue forjando mucho más.
今天的事实是，我们真的很享受日常生活，我们整天都在一起，喝酒，玩恶作剧。
And today the truth is that we really enjoy everyday life, we are together all day, drinking mate, playing trick.
Y hoy en día la verdad es que disfrutamos un montón el día a día, estamos todo el día juntos, tomando mate, jugando al truco.
并谈论任何事情。
and talking about whatever.
y hablando de lo que sea.
显然那里很有趣。
So obviously it's a lot of fun in there.
Así que obviamente se disfruta mucho ahí adentro.
莱安德罗和罗德里戈非常外向。
Leandro and Rodrigo are very outgoing.
Leandro y Rodrigo son muy extrovertidos.
你在那个最有趣的团体中扮演什么角色？
What is your role within that funniest group?
¿Cuál es tu rol dentro de ese grupo más jodón?
平衡。
The balance.
El equilibrio.
你看，我……不，连这个都不是。
You see, I... No, not even that.
Viste, yo... No, ni tan eso.
也没有另一个，作为中间人找到平衡。
nor the other, finding the balance to be there as an intermediary.
ni tan lo otro, encontrar el equilibrio como para estar ahí de intermediario.
因为这两个整天都很高，所以你必须时不时地
because these two are very high all day, so every now and then you have to be
porque estos dos están todo el día muy arriba, entonces cada tanto hay que estar
冷静点，但是不，我们……我们很紧张，我们整天都在一起，我们一个人什么也做不了。
Be calmer, but no, we are... We are very intense, we are together all day, we can't do anything alone.
Estar más tranquilos, pero no, estamos... Somos muy intensos, estamos todo el día juntos, no podemos hacer nada solos.
所以我认为我们花这么多时间在一起是有原因的。
So I think there's a reason we spend so much time together like this.
Entonces creo que por algo estamos así tanto tiempo juntos.
但是，嘿，正如我告诉你的，这非常令人愉快。
But hey, it's very enjoyable, as I told you.
Pero bueno, se disfruta mucho, como te dije.
就像瘦子说的，活着的时候就玩。
As the skinny guy said, you play when you live.
Como decía el flaco, se juega cuando se vive.
你是平衡的一部分。
You are the part of the balance.
Vos sos la parte del equilibrio.
是的，是的，我也无法全部跟上他们，时常我们不得不放慢速度，因为......
Yes, yes, I can't all keep up with them either, every so often we have to slow it down a little because...
Sí, sí, yo tampoco podemos estar todos al ritmo de ellos, cada tanto hay que bajarlo un poco porque...
嗯，他们非常激烈，充满活力。
Well, they are very intense, very charged.
pues son muy intensos, muy cargosos.
那么好吧，简而言之...
So well, one in short...
Entonces bueno, uno en definitiva...
充当他们之间的中介。
acts as an intermediary between them.
hace de intermediario entre ellos.
我放在选拔表上的第一个项目是奥运会。
The first one I put at the selection table was the Olympic Games.
La primera que te puse a la mesa de la selección fueron los Juegos Olímpicos.
对此我记得什么？
What do I remember about that?
¿Qué recuerdo de aquello?
参加这届奥运会的比赛队伍。
to the match team in these Olympic Games.
al equipo de match en estos Juegos Olímpicos.
我知道你看过比赛，也知道你如何分析比赛。
I know you saw the games, how you analyze it.
Sé que viste los partidos, cómo lo analizás.
哪些球员引起了您的注意？
And which players caught your attention?
¿Y qué jugadores llamaron la atención?
2016年里约奥运会，当时发生了整个AFA问题。
In Rio 2016, when there was the whole AFA issue.
En Río 2016, cuando estaba todo el tema de la AFA.
我认为在足球方面我们无法给予我们什么
and I think that football-wise we couldn't give what we
y creo que futbolísticamente no pudimos dar lo que
我们必须付出什么。
what we had to give.
lo que teníamos para dar.
但是，嘿，作为一次生活经历，身处其中、看到一切真是令人难以置信……
But hey, as a lived experience it was something incredible to be in there, to see everything...
Pero bueno, como experiencia vivida fue algo increíble estar ahí adentro, ver toda...
看看你在奥运村看到的所有人。
See all the people you see in there, in the Olympic Village.
Ver todas las personas que ves ahí adentro, en la Villa Olímpica.
作为一次经历，这是令人难以置信的，但我告诉过你，从足球的角度来看，显然......
As an experience it was incredible, but I told you, from a football perspective, obviously...
Como experiencia fue increíble, pero ya te digo, futbolísticamente, obviamente que...
这不是我们想要的。
which was not what we wanted.
que no fue lo que queríamos.
回到现在，
And going back a little to now,
Y volviendo un poco a lo de ahora,
我认为
and I think that
y creo que
是的，小伙子们表现得很好，他们很好地代表了所有阿根廷人。
Yes, the boys did very well, they represented all Argentinians very well.
que sí, los chicos lo hicieron muy bien, nos representaron muy bien a todos los argentinos.
明显地...
Obviously...
Obviamente que...
与法国队的比赛是一个细节，因为他们发现自己进球了
The match with France was a detail because they found themselves with a goal
El partido con Francia fue un detalle porque ellos se encuentran con un gol
比赛很早，然后我们就有很多机会扳平比分。
early and then we had many chances to tie it.
tempranero y después nosotros tuvimos muchas ocasiones para empatarlo.
留在任何球员身边都很困难，因为看看每个人表现出的水平和球员数量。
It is difficult to stay with any player because look at the level that everyone showed and the number of players.
Es difícil quedarte con algún jugador porque fíjate el nivel que mostraron todos y la cantidad de jugadores.
那里有很多优秀的球员，但很难坚持其中之一。
There are so many good players out there and it's difficult to stick with one.
de buenos jugadores que hay y es difícil quedarte con uno.
我认为有一个
I think there is a
Creo que hay una
非常漂亮的垃圾即将到来，而且很明显
very nice litter that is coming and well obviously
muy linda camada la que viene y bueno obviamente que
可悲的是，因为它逃避了细节。
sadly because it escapes details.
con tristeza porque se escapa por detalles.
但是，嘿，显然我们都很自豪。
But hey, obviously we are all proud.
Pero bueno, obviamente que estamos todos orgullosos.
关于他们所做的事情以及他们如何代表所有阿根廷人。
About what they did and how they represented all Argentines.
De lo que hicieron y cómo nos representaron a todos los argentinos.
对于你和每个人来说，这都是清楚的。
For you and for everyone, it is clear.
Para vos y para todos, está claro.
他们必须保持俱乐部的最高水平，因为落后的男孩是
They are going to have to maintain that top level that the clubs have because the boys who come behind are
van a tener que mantener ese nivel top que tienen los clubes porque los chicos que vienen atrás están
他们在外面，正在看着赛道。
They're outside, they're looking at the track.
Están fuera, están viendo pista.
是的，是的。
Yes, yes.
Sí, sí.
而且，你说的就是教练每次说的……
Furthermore, what you say is what the coach says every time...
Además, esto que decís vos lo dice el entrenador cada vez que…
谁看到我们就和我们在一起。
who sees us and we get together.
que nos ve y nos juntamos.
正如我之前告诉过你的，门槛非常高，请注意
As I told you before, the bar is very high, notice that there
Como te dije anteriormente, la vara está muy alta, fíjate que ahí
顶级球员，有很多等级制度，显然还有男孩
top-level players, with a lot of hierarchy and obviously the boys
jugadores de primer nivel, de mucha jerarquía y obviamente que los chicos
他们从后面过来，他们推过来，那么好......
They come from behind, they come pushing, so well...
que vienen atrás, vienen empujando, entonces bueno...
这就是美丽的所在，最终让它变得越来越美丽
That's what's beautiful and that's ultimately what makes it more and more
eso es lo lindo y eso en definitiva lo que hace que cada vez sea más
一切都变得更加困难，同时水平也提高了。
everything is harder and at the same time the levels are raised.
más duro todo y a su vez que se eleven los niveles.
因为谁都不能放松，因为他们知道他们背后有另一个……
because neither can relax because they know they have the other behind...
porque ninguno puede relajarse porque sabe que tiene al otro atrás...
镐和铲子。
Pick and shovel.
Pico y pala.
即将到来的赛季的目标是什么？
What are the objectives for the upcoming season?
¿Cuáles son los objetivos para la temporada que arranca?
在欧洲，你下赛季的目标是什么？
In Europe, what are your goals for the upcoming season?
en Europa, ¿cuáles son tus objetivos para la temporada que arranca?
回来、重新开始总是好的。
It's always nice to come back, start again.
Siempre es lindo volver, empezar otra vez.
季前赛是和你的队友、球队在一起的。
a preseason to be with your teammates, with the team.
una pretemporada estar con tus compañeros, con el equipo.
那么，好吧。
So, well.
Entonces, bueno.
将有时间开始思考。
There will be time to start thinking.
ya habrá tiempo para ponerte a pensar.
将会发生什么？
What is going to happen?
¿Qué va a pasar?
但现在我会享受这个。
But for now I'll enjoy this.
Pero de momento disfrutaré esto.
显然，一个人设定个人目标。
Obviously one sets personal goals.
Obviamente que uno se va poniendo objetivos personales.
每天，所以没什么。
daily, so nothing.
a diario, así que nada.
你还有哪些未完成的梦想？
What are your pending dreams?
¿Cuáles son tus sueños pendientes?
事实是，这是一个有点问题......
The truth is that it is a bit of a question...
La verdad que es una pregunta un poco...
一点点涵盖很多内容，明确地设定短期目标。
A little bit that covers a lot, definitively one sets short-term goals.
Un poco que abarca mucho, definitiva uno se va poniendo objetivos a corto plazo.
正如我当时告诉你的，我的梦想是喜欢……
As I told you at the time, my dream was to like...
Como te dije en su momento, mi sueño era gustar...
首发中锋，随后他们在阿根廷国家队首次亮相。
in the first center, then they made their debut in the Argentine national team.
en la primera de central, después se debutan en la selección argentina.
这就是为什么我告诉你，生活会把你带到你意想不到或想象不到的时刻和地方。
That's why I tell you, life takes you to moments and places that you don't expect or imagine.
Por eso te digo, la vida te va llevando a momentos y a lugares que uno no lo espera ni lo imagina.
显然我还可以拥有一百万个梦想。
So obviously I can have a million more dreams.
Así que obviamente puedo tener un millón de sueños más.
还有一百万个要实现的事情、目标。
and a million more things to achieve, objectives.
y un millón de cosas más por conseguir, objetivos.
无论是足球还是非足球。
whether football or non-football.
ya sea futbolístico o extrafutbolístico.
所以我想如果我必须保持梦想......
So I think that if I have to keep a dream...
Entonces creo que si me tengo que quedar con un sueño...
这会很小，因为最终人们总是想要更多。
It would be little because ultimately one always wants more.
Sería poco porque en definitiva uno siempre quiere más.
他总是想继续克服口音，我认为还有很多梦想悬而未决。
He always wants to continue overcoming accents and I think there are still many dreams pending.
Siempre quiere seguir superando acentos y creo que sueños quedan todavía muchos pendientes.
如果我告诉你一个梦想，对我来说这不是一个梦想，但我认为它就是这样
and if I tell you one that would be a dream, for me it is not a dream, but I think it is like that
y si yo te digo uno que sería un sueño, para mí no es un sueño, pero yo creo que es así
梦想可能是参加下一届世界杯，也可能不是梦想。
A dream may be to be in the next World Cup or it may not be a dream.
Un sueño puede llegar a ser estar en el próximo mundial o no es un sueño.
是的，显然。
Yes, obviously.
Si, obvio.
是的，那是一个梦。
Yes that is a dream.
Si eso es un sueño.
梦想就是赢得欧冠冠军，这就是为什么我告诉你，有很多事情，梦想就是赢得冠军。
A dream would be to win a Champions League, that's why I tell you, there are a lot of things, a dream would be to win.
un sueño sería ganar una Champions, por eso te digo, hay un montón de cosas, un sueño sería ganar
托特纳姆热刺队的冠军我们还没有能够实现，显然有很多事情需要我们去完成。
a title with Tottenham that we still haven't been able to achieve, there are obviously many things that one
un título con el Tottenham que todavía no lo pudimos hacer, hay muchas cosas obviamente que uno
它正在制定，但不是那么遥远的目标，而是短期目标。
It is being set, but not such distant goals, but rather short objectives.
Se va poniendo, pero no metas tan lejanas, sino objetivos cortos.
对于他们所说的，我现在想要的就是享受那个伴侣。
Regarding what they are saying, what I want now is to enjoy that mate.
Sobre lo que están decís yo lo que quiero ahora es disfrutar ese mate.
你在其中吗？
Are you in it?
¿Estás en eso?
是的，正如我告诉过你的，我是享受日常生活的人之一。
Yes, I am one of those who enjoy everyday life, as I told you.
Sí, yo soy de esos que disfrutan el día a día, como te dije.
我享受今天的每一天、旅程，现在我喜欢有一些朋友在家
I enjoy the day to day, the journey, today and now I enjoy having some mates at home
disfruto el día a día, el camino, hoy y ahora disfruto de tomarme unos mates en mi casa
明天开始进行医学研究，前往俱乐部，再次见到你的队友。
Tomorrow started with medical studies, getting to the club, seeing your teammates again.
Mañana arrancaba con los estudios médicos, llegar al club, ver a tus compañeros otra vez.
我很享受这一切。
I enjoy all that.
Disfruto todo eso.
我不再继续思考，但是……
I don't take my head any further, but...
No me llevo la cabeza más allá, sino...
但目标要短，享受每一天和每一刻。
but short goals and enjoy the day to day and the moment.
sino objetivos cortos y disfrutar el día a día y el momento.
说到享受和梦想。
And speaking of enjoying and dreams.
Y hablando de disfrutar y de sueños.
这个位置占据了这个头部的中心位置，它不经常飞翔，因为那是日复一日的，但是
central that the place occupies in this head that does not fly much because that is day to day, but that
central que el lugar ocupa en esta cabeza que mucho no vuela porque eso es del día a día, pero que
你占据什么位置？
What place do you occupy?
¿Qué lugar ocupas?
你最近去过体育场吗？
Were you recently at the stadium?
¿Estuviste hace poquito en el estadio?
您谈到了核心时间。
You talked about core time.
Hablaste del tiempo central.
是的，是的，显然它是中心。
Yes, yes, obviously it is central.
Sí, sí, obviamente que es central.
我的一生，我的事业，占据了我很多。
My whole life, my career, occupies a lot in me.
Ocupa mucho en mí lo que fue toda mi vida, mi trayectoria.
我是俱乐部的球迷。
I am a fan of the club.
Soy hincha del club.
我一直梦想在那里出道，所以每次
I always dreamed of debuting there, so every time
Siempre soñé con debutar ahí, entonces cada vez que
当我回来时，我会尝试去那里，我会去法庭，现在我很幸运......
When I come back I try to be there, I go to the court, now I am lucky to...
que vuelvo trato de estar, voy a la cancha, ahora tengo la suerte de...
体验我兄弟的存在，看他打球。
to experience that my brother is there, to see him play.
de vivir que mi hermano está ahí, de verlo jugar.
虽然享受，但远离也更痛苦。
Although one enjoys it, one also suffers much more being far away.
Si bien uno lo disfruta, también se sufre mucho más estando lejos.
但是，嘿，现在我能够去那里度假，去野外，也带着我的女儿，这是非常激动人心的事情。
But hey, now I was able to be there on vacation, go to the field, take my daughter too, which was something very emotional.
Pero bueno, ahora pude estar ahí en la vacación, ir a la cancha, llevar a mi hija también, que fue algo muy emotivo.
因为比赛那天距离他首次亮相才刚刚九年。
because it had just been nine years since he had debuted on the day of the match.
porque justo se habían cumplido nueve años de que había debutado justo el día ese del partido.
所以这是非常感人的，因为你也看到了
So it was very emotional because you also see
entonces fue muy emotivo porque ves también
整个旅程，我脑海中浮现出很多画面，能够带我女儿去野外。
The whole journey, many images that come to mind, being able to take my daughter to the field.
Todo el recorrido, muchas imágenes que te vienen a la cabeza, poder llevar a mi hija a la cancha.
这是一次很好的经历，所以我显然没有什么总是记得的
It was a nice experience so well nothing I always keep in mind obviously
fue una experiencia linda entonces bueno nada siempre lo tengo presente obviamente que
永远感激他们一直以来给予我的爱，并且至今仍继续给予我。
eternally grateful for the love they always gave me and continue to give me to this day.
eternamente agradecido por el cariño que me brindaron siempre y me siguen brindando hasta el día de hoy.
这是给阿根廷人的一条信息，他们对埃斯卡洛内塔和你们这群人感到满意。
A message for the Argentines, who are happy with the escaloneta, with this group of you.
Un mensaje para los argentinos, que están felices con la escaloneta, con este grupo de ustedes.
你会给他们什么信息？
What messages would you give them?
¿Qué mensajes les darías?
享受，继续享受这些时刻。
Enjoy, continue enjoying these moments.
Que disfruten, que sigan disfrutando estos momentos.
它们并不是每天都会发生，虽然看起来很容易，但过去和现在都是一段非常艰难的旅程。
They don't happen every day, although it seems easy, it was and is a very difficult journey.
No se dan todos los días, si bien parece fácil, fue y es un recorrido muy difícil.
正在发生的事情。
the one that was happening.
el que se estuvo dando.
好吧，正如我们之前所说，
And well, as we said before,
Y bueno, como dijimos antes,
我们不必放松，我们知道前面还有很多美好的事情，但是哦，好吧。
We don't have to relax, we know that there are many very nice things ahead, but oh well.
No hay que relajarse, sabemos que vienen muchas cosas por delante muy lindas, pero bueno.
最重要的是粉丝的感受
The most important thing is that the fan feels
Lo más importante es que el hincha se sienta
这支球队反映，每次轮到他们比赛时，无论是友谊赛还是其他什么，
reflected by this team, that every time it is their turn to play, whether it is a friendly or whatever,
reflejado por esta selección, que cada vez que le toca jugar, ya sea un amistoso o lo que sea,
这一切都是因为盾牌和颜色。
All because of the shield and the colors.
Todo por el escudo y los colores.
谢谢！
¡Gracias!